

CONTACT

Linkedin in/paul-cartau

Email paul.cartau@gmail.com

Address Paris, Bordeaux, Full Remote

Phone +33 6 24 78 12 26

TECH SKILLS

Core Stack

Typescript / Javascript / HTML CSS / React / React native / Node.js / NestJS / Express / Java Spring / NextJs / Remix / Python / ASP.NET

Cloud / Devops

AWS / GCP / Docker / Kubernetes / Gitlab CI / Github Actions / Scaleway / OVH / PM2 / Bitbucket / CI/CD / Sentry

Databases & ORM

MongoDB / PostgreSQL / SQL / Redis / SQLite / Prisma / Sequelize / TypeORM / Mongoose

Other

TDD / Clean Code / Clean Architecture / Pair programming / Algorithmic thinking / Agile development / Design System

SOFT SKILLS

Lean Managment / Product Managment / Inovation / Company Strategy / UX / UI / Problem solving

ACTIVITIES

Professional boxing

Teaching children who can't go on vacation

how to code

Some of books I've read:

- Robert C.Martin Books
- Intercom Papers
- Learning to Scale / Lean Startup
- Cracking the coding Interview

Paul CARTAU

Fullstack Developer

A highly motivated and experienced Fullstack Developer with a strong understanding of web development. My experience in the industry has allowed me to develop a strong eye for detail and an inherent ability to troubleshoot and solve complex problems.

EXPERIENCE

Fullstack Developer 2019 - Today

B4Finance, Tealer, Tealerlab, Zerance, Moba, Ifocop, Greta, Crocollect, HelloZack

Worked on different freelance projects as Fullstack developer, Tech Lead, and Trainer.

- Creation of MVP from scratch with the founders
- Estimating and writing specifications
- Implementation of good devs practices in existing teams
- · Face-to-face teaching
- UX/UI Design integrations
- Sprint Reviews, Tech Reporting

React / React native / Python DRF / AWS / GCP / Docker / Kubernetes / Java Spring / Typescript / NodeJs / MongoDB / PostgreSQL / NextJs / HTML/CSS

CTO & Co-Founder 2020 - 2022

Reply

Launch of a social networking startup. My role was to manage the whole technical side of the company, in addition to participating in strategic decisions. Acquired by other entrepreneurs.

- Global deployment (Cloud, Languages, Databases, Compliance)
- Design of the global application architecture (micro-services)
- Management of the tech team
- Strategic committee on technical and business issues
- Implementation of good dev practices (TDD / Clean Code / Lean Strategy)
- Sprint Reviews, Tech Reporting, Invests Pitch

React native / NodeJs / Docker / AWS / MongoDB / PM2 / Express / Sentry

Fullstack Developer Jan 2020 - Jun 2020

Orthoin3D

Tech Lead in medical Startup. My role was to manage the existing tech team, while developing the key features of the application.

- Design of the global architecture of the application
- Implementation of agile method tools within the technical team
- Creation of key features of the application
- Tech Reporting / Helping in recruitement

React / Docker / OVH / Python DRF

EDUCATION

School 42 2017 - 2019

Digital Technologies Architect

- Peer-to-peer computer development on low-level languages.
- Mastering good IT development practices